okay this next example is a it's a tough
one for me because it was from the
Mosconi Cup 2019 and I put it in this
line of videos to show you first of all
that I don't only want to show the the
great things that I've done on and look
at every rack I ran but also a rack
where I made a complete blunder of a
choice and this is because of the
highest level of pressure and I go over
this in the course and this is face
number four if you talk about levels of
pressure there's actually four phases
and what it does to you if you're
breathing poorly if the pressure can get
to you it affects the way you think
sometimes and we're gonna see a good
example of that in this rack that was
actually a pretty decent shot I almost
hooked Skylar there wasn't easy so I
wasn't too unsatisfied with this one and
the balls are playing pretty funky I
can't see from here if he can see that
ball or not but I was struggling in this
tournament they said a couple of reasons
which are not very interesting to
mention here but if I just focus on
myself at a hard time I lost the first
couple of matches I missed the ball in
the opening doubles game to have a
chance to win that match so it affected
my confidence a little bit and I was I
was battling uphill which was pretty
hard and it's only races to five and
it's great player so if you don't get
off to a good start
it it's tough you can fall behind really
quickly so here I'm down 1-0 I was
jumping really good this tournament I
remember that so here we get a jump shot
and after this we can see the mental
error that I make first of all this jump
was really nice but right here I'm
totally relaxed now looking at this
layout from up
stop and I'm thinking just draw the ball
back a hair see I have very little angle
just draw it back about three inches to
the middle of the table and take the
position from there but because I wasn't
feeling that good I want to try and get
closer to the ball and I totally
misjudged the cloth I was even afraid of
scratching in the left corner from what
we're looking at now so it was a mental
error my mind was not functioning in a
normal way because of the pressure so
clearly I'm I'm frustrated because I
also have the shot clock I had a big
opportunity to make it 1-1 I blow that I
already lost three matches before that
so of course I'm not happy and I have to
go over this ball kick at it I have no
time and it's tough shot so looking back
at the layout I could have gone three
rails on the three ball get on the four
and I would have had really nice
position so this is an example that were
all human and that we're all struggling
sometimes but it's like brené Brown says
and I find this super fascinating she
says if you're gonna go into the arena
and do what you love to do you're gonna
get your ass kicked and what that means
is it's not it doesn't mean that you're
gonna lose every time it means that the
better you get the more you're gonna be
in the spotlight and the more you will
be criticized and the reason that I
didn't read or cared about any of the
criticism is actually because also what
she said and I find this very
fascinating quote and it's probably the
best one that I've learned last year she
said I'm I'm only interested in your
feedback about what I've done in the
arena if you're also in the arena with
me getting your ass kicked and I just
find that so
cool because it means that if you also
put yourself out there and take chances
and try to get the best out of yourself
try to be in the spotlight take risks
then you know how it is and that's
that's super cool but if you're just
sitting there in the cheap seats and not
doing anything not taking any chances
you have dreams but you don't go after
them then you just shouldn't say
anything or I'm just not gonna listen to
it so it helped me with my attitude
about criticism and I just I just wanted
to share that because it can guard you
against people that might be criticizing
you and if you value what you do and you
want to go out there and do it because
it makes you happy but it makes you feel
alive then just stick with it and you'll
get through it so that was an example of
a bad mental error but I'm still alive
and I'm keep coming back so there you go
okay the next example is from the
Whirlpool masters again first the finals
versus Shane of course a special
tournament for me with the injury and
the reason I chose this Rack is just to
show you that if you go through a
tournament or even some matches
sometimes and you've done all the hard
work mentally sticking with it
maybe you weren't feeling that great for
a while you had some poor matches but
sometimes these poor matches where
you're really struggling is also the
best training and the best practice I
was doing a little dance there to try to
get the one ball a little further but
what I've learned over the years is that
that is actually super good training so
now you get a few hours off or maybe a
day off and you've trained yourself to
become a better player actually within
the tournament by going through those
tough matches and then here you can see
that after a few matches in this
tournament my confidence was really
starting to grow
and sometimes maybe you would push out
here but I was starting to really feel
good I knew the table and I said you
know what boom I'm going I'm going
through the front door and there you see
the reward if you take assertive action
and especially in nine ball you can't
abduct forever you gotta go out there
and take it if you want to win because
these players that you're facing are
such high level you have to take it away
you can't have sometimes let it to the
table so it's just a great example of
really starting to find a groove within
distr namond and of course the balls are
laying pretty nice now but it was just a
great final because of the injury I was
really I had a hard time of course
coming back I was out of stroke but
within the tournament I was working my
way in stroke and because the last two
matches of this event versus Carl and
Shane I was pain free and that really
meant for me that the change were coming
off I had no fear of my body anymore of
pain and it just it just escalated from
there my my feeling of the table my
confidence
it just came back of course these balls
are not the toughest shots hurt but it's
a great example that you will get
rewarded
Shane's having a bit of a hard time
there himself in the chair he has to
work on that composure and some
self-talk which is tough if you're down
and it's a winter break and the guys
getting shots after the break then you
feel like oh man this is gonna be a hard
one and you really have to have to stay
with it and wait for your chances so
just a quick example there of a nice
reward after hard work now you see
1 9 the title was on the line
[Music]